module five mvp does not stand for most valuable player in this case it is minimal viable product
what is the least amount of service that i can do that i can explain to get the customer to say yes
sounds bad but it will once again help that repeatable process if you don't have any clients
what minimal and in the simplest way can i present my product or service whatever it is
for the customer to understand it um if it's a software how can i create 70 of it going back to
that 70 rule to get a sale you don't have to be perfect here so understand um that part the offer
right the content versus the brand these are all very different um you don't need to go all the way
and say we are going to completely transform let's go with a financial advisor here we are going to
completely transform your portfolio doesn't need to be that vast and it doesn't need to be so broad
right you probably once again want to pick a specific niche and you once again want to pick
um something a little bit more understanding right a little bit more specific i will fix all of your
um bundled etfs i will not only take a look at your current portfolio i will see where it's lacking
and that's your current mvp offer right and then i'll make some suggestions along the way and then
you can choose me built on trust after a week or so of different sales calls right you're one pager
um no one's in especially in this day and age no one's going to read a 50 page portfolio
no one's going to do the due diligence of that um unless your audience or your customers are lawyers
right even then they probably won't read it they're probably going to throw it into chat gbt and say
summarize or something so make it clear make it one page so someone on the other side even if it's like
a fourth or fifth grader right understand that that's where the reading level should be in terms
of their understanding or make it simple make sure they can understand it one pager right um
make it clean i guess that was the consensus for that bullet point the deliverable ladder
audit checklist going back to your financial planning uh service you already have an existing
portfolio we'll audit it check it and see where you can improve the setup okay what does onboarding
for your customer look like do they need your vanguard password are they moving money from one account
to another how long is that going to take do they need to sign stuff along the way map that out the
customer onboarding is uh often looked over aspect that can just really elevate your service if you
understand exactly what's going to happen um in their future and map it out they're going to super
appreciate it and make you a little bit more experienced um here's the sprint along the lines of um
i'm going to change xyz in one week two weeks three months map it out timeline specific so when it's
friday after one week they don't have to call you and say what's what's happening what's going on
um i'd like an update it would just be oh by week one this should be happening and it is and you can
just say hey the thing that we talked about about week one that's happening today or that happened
today give those types of updates that the client will very much appreciate it um and this is if this
is a recurring service that's what that retainer model might look like if you're paying them monthly
talk about it right protecting your time i always call this scope creep what extra is going to happen
if they're calling you consistently every single day now they're stepping out of boundaries we have a
weekly call every wednesday um we are going to only look at ten thousand dollars of your portfolio not
the rest um set those limits up during the sales call during the onboarding experience whatever it may
be set boundaries because that might lead into your uh different product um or service packaging
if you want extra attention you're going to have to pay for it and now you're paying for
package gold platinum right
uh this is just reiterating protect your time
avoid custom bills make sure this is a repeatable simple process you don't really again want to have
those snowflake clients where all of them are taking up all of your account management time
or your account manager's time or your sales time build out the timeline build out the specific
um cadence of when you're going to meet with them how often um they should be asking you for updates
they should understand that before they even sign on the dotted line but if that's not
doable for your specific type of service after they do that they should be given a literal timeline
of things that will happen by week one week two month three month six right
what not to do we're really hitting the um head here with the with this no custom proposals for
every lead simple repeatable right um continuing on minimal minimum deliverable definition
what is the service that's going to be repeatable simple simple simple is going to make sure that your
uh sales are going to continue deliverable name don't make it some generic thing make it like
my minimum package um gold package make it a little bit more nice for them to hear right
abide by all of these things abide by all of these rules
if you're ready to sell here are the tools that you're going to need you're going to need to make
sure that if this is a digital sale service they can input their credit card they can make an ach
transfer a wire transfer uh zelle payment uh venmo payment uh apple pay text message payment
all of those things should be working by the time you're already having those conversations so this
would be helpful before you have the sales call um before you have any of the outreach this would be
helpful they're not must-haves it's just going to make everything so much smoother if you need to
continue uh your conversation it didn't sell right after your sales your first sales call who would have
guest calendar link right send it for um oh are you available tomorrow are you available friday and
don't be so pushy here no need late let them think about it whatever that service is send them a
calendar link on the call going to up your showing rates um for that second sales conversation
onboarding dock make sure they look through it beforehand before they sign up so they understand
the future of what that service relationship is going to look like um and then have a delivery
sop understand exactly what you're going to do for that minimum service they need to understand it as
well right what are the first steps once they pay here the key takeaways on to the next module
you